Preliminary Inventory of the John B. Cornell papers
Hoover Institution Archives
John B. Cornell papers
1965-1968
86001
Hoover Institution Archives
23 manuscript boxes, 8 card file boxes (10.8 linear feet)
Questionnaires, field notes, and statistics, relating to demographic characteristics of Japanese emigrants to the Noroeste region of Brazil. Includes studies summarizing findings, and a case study of Japanese in Getulina, São Paulo State.
Cornell, John B. (John Bilheimer), 1921-
Access
One study in Box 23 may not be quoted without permission of J. B. Cornell.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1986.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
American anthropologist.
Scope and Content of Collection
Questionnaires, field notes, and statistics, relating to demographic characteristics of Japanese emigrants to the Noroeste region of Brazil. Includes studies summarizing findings, and a case study of Japanese in Getulina, São Paulo State.
Getulina (Brazil); Japanese--Brazil.; Minorities--Brazil.
- Family Background, Part 2, Pais do Informante, 1968 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Family Background, Part 2, Informante, 1968 (Box-folder 1: 2)
- 1-Junqueiropolis, circa 1968 (Box-folder 1:3)
- 2-Boa Visit, circa 1968 (Box-folder 1: 4)
- 3-Junqueiropolis, circa 1968 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- 4-1a Aliança Getulina (cidade), circa 1968 (Box-folder 1: 6)
- 5-Aliança, circa 1968 (Box-folder 1: 7-8)
- 6-Guatapará, circa 1968 (Box-folder 1: 8)
- 7-Mirandopolis 1a Aliança, circa 1968 (Box-folder 1: 9)
- 8-Mirandopolis 2a Aliança, circa 1968 (Box-folder 1: 10)
- 9-Mirandopolis 3a Aliança, circa 1968 (Box-folder 1: 11)
- 10-Santo Antonio da Platina, circa 1968 (Box-folder 1: 12)
- 11-Suzano, circa 1968 (Box-folder 1: 13)
- 1-1 (1-39), 1966 (Box-folder 2: 1)
- 1-3 (80-119), 1966 (Box-folder 2: 2)
- 1-4, circa 1966 (Box-folder 2: 3)
- 2-2 (40-79), 1966 (Box-folder 2: 3-4)
- 2-Yamato (Box-folder 2: 5)
- 3-Boa Vista, circa 1966 (Box-folder 2: 6)
- 4-Getulina, 1966 (Box-folder 2: 7)
- 5-Getulina, 1966 (Box-folder 2: 8-9)
- 6-1 (1-39), 1966 (Box-folder 2: 9)
- 6-2 (40-79), 1966 (Box-folder 2: 10)
- 6-3 (80- ), 1966 (Box-folder 2: 11)
- 12-Juquiá, circa 1966 (Box-folder 2: 12)
- 7-1 (1-39), 1966 (Box-folder 3: 1)
- 7-2 (40- ), 1966 (Box-folder 3: 2)
- 8-2a Aliança Mirandopolis, 1966 (Box-folder 3: 3)
- 9-Mirandopolis 3a Aliança, 1966 (Box-folder 3: 4)
- 10-Santo Antonio da Platina, 1966 (Box-folder 3: 5)
- 11-1 (1-39) Suzano, 1966 (Box-folder 3: 6)
- 11-2 (40-179) Suzano (Box-folder 3: 7)
- 11-3 (80-119) Suzano, 1966 (Box-folder 3: 8)
- 11-4 (120-159) Suzano, 1966 (Box-folder 3: 8)
- 11-5 (160-199) Suzano, 1966 (Box-folder 3: 9)
- 11-6 (200-239) Suzano, 1967 (Box-folder 3: 11)
- 11-7 (240- ) Suzano, 1996 (Box-folder 3: 12)
- 12- Juquiá, 1962-1996
- Pesquisas Sôbre os Universitários Nisseis, circa 1966
  - 0001-0009, circa 1966 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - 0010-0019, circa 1966 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - 0020-0029, circa 1966 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - 0030-0039, circa 1966 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - 0040-0049, circa 1966 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - 0050-0059, circa 1966 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - 0060-0069, circa 1966 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - 0070-0079, circa 1966 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - 0080-0089, circa 1966 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - 0090-0099, circa 1966 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - 0100-0109, circa 1966 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - 0110-0119, circa 1966 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - 0120-0129, circa 1966 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - 0130-0139, circa 1966 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - 0140-0149, circa 1966 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - 0150-0159, circa 1966 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - 0160-0169, circa 1966 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - 0170-0179, circa 1966 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - 0180-0189, circa 1966 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - 0190-0199, circa 1966 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - 0200-0209, circa 1966 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - 0210-0219, circa 1966 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - 0220-0229, circa 1966 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - 0230-0239, circa 1966 (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - 0240-0249, circa 1966 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - 0250-0259, circa 1966 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - 0260-0269, circa 1966 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - 0270-0279, circa 1966 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - 0280-0289, circa 1966 (Box-folder 7: 7)
  - 0290-0299, circa 1966 (Box-folder 7: 8)
  - 0300-0309, circa 1966 (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - 0310-0319, circa 1966 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - 0320-0329, circa 1966 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - 0330-0339, circa 1966 (Box-folder 8: 3)
  - 0340-0349, circa 1966 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - 0350-0359, circa 1966 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - 0360-0369, circa 1966 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - 0370-0379, circa 1966 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - 0380-0389, circa 1966 (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - 0390-0399, circa 1966 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - 0400-0409, circa 1966 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - 0410-0419, circa 1966 (Box-folder 9: 3)
  - 0420-0429, circa 1966 (Box-folder 9: 4)
  - 0430-0439, circa 1966 (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - 0440-0449, circa 1966 (Box-folder 9: 6)
  - 0450-0459, circa 1966 (Box-folder 9: 7)
  - 0460-0469, circa 1966 (Box-folder 9: 8)
  - 0470-0479, circa 1966 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - 0480-0489, circa 1966 (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - 0490-0499, circa 1966 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - 0500-0509, 1966 (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - 0510-0519, 1966 (Box-folder 11: 2)
  - 0520-0529, 1966 (Box-folder 11: 3)
  - 0530-0539, 1966 (Box-folder 11: 4)
  - 0540-0549, 1966 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - 0550-0559, 1966 (Box-folder 12: 2)
  - 0560-0569, 1966 (Box-folder 12: 3)
  - 0570-0579, 1966 (Box-folder 12: 4)
  - 0580-0589, 1966 (Box-folder 12: 5)
  - 0590-0599, 1966 (Box-folder 12: 6)
  - 0600-0609, 1966 (Box-folder 12: 7)
  - 0610-0619, 1966 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - 0620-0629, 1966 (Box-folder 13: 2)
  - 0630-0639, 1966 (Box-folder 13: 3)
  - 0640-0649, 1966 (Box-folder 13: 4)
  - 0650-0659, 1966 (Box-folder 13: 5)
  - 0660-0669, 1966 (Box-folder 13: 6)
  - 0670-0679, 1966 (Box-folder 13: 7)
  - 0680-0689, 1966 (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - 0690-0699, 1966 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - 0700-0709, 1966 (Box-folder 14: 2)
  - 0710-0719, 1966 (Box-folder 14: 3)
  - 0720-0729, 1966 (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - 0730-0739, 1966 (Box-folder 14: 5)
  - 0740-0749, 1966 (Box-folder 14: 5-6)
  - 0750-0759, 1966 (Box-folder 14: 7)
  - 0760-0769, 1966 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - 0770-0779, 1966 (Box-folder 15: 2)
  - 0780-0789, 1966 (Box-folder 15: 3)
  - 0790-0799, 1966 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - 0800-0809, 1966 (Box-folder 15: 5)
  - 0810-0819, 1966 (Box-folder 15: 6)
  - 0820-0829, 1966 (Box-folder 15: 7)
  - 0830-0839, 1966 (Box-folder 16: 1)
  - 0840-0849, 1966 (Box-folder 16: 2)
  - 0850-0859, 1966 (Box-folder 16: 3)
  - 0860-0869, 1966 (Box-folder 16: 4)
  - 0870-0879, 1966 (Box-folder 16: 5)
  - 0880-0889, 1966 (Box-folder 16: 6)
  - 0890-0899, 1966 (Box-folder 16: 7)
  - 0900-0909, 1966 (Box-folder 17: 1)
  - 0910-0919, 1966 (Box-folder 17: 2)
  - 0920-0929, 1966 (Box-folder 17: 3)
  - 0930-0939, 1966 (Box-folder 17: 4)
  - 0940-0949, 1966 (Box-folder 17: 5)
  - 0950-0959, 1966 (Box-folder 17: 6)
  - 0960-0969, 1966 (Box-folder 17: 7)
  - 0970-0979, 1966 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - 0980-0989, 1966 (Box-folder 18: 2)
  - 0990-0999, 1966 (Box-folder 18: 3)
  - 1000-1009, 1966 (Box-folder 18: 4)
  - 1010-1019, 1966 (Box-folder 19: 1)
  - 1020-1030, 1966 (Box-folder 19: 2)
  - 1030-1039, 1966 (Box-folder 19: 3)
  - 1040-1049, 1966 (Box-folder 19: 4)
  - 1050-1059, 1966 (Box-folder 19: 5)
  - 1060-1069, 1966 (Box-folder 19: 6)
  - 1070-1079, 1966 (Box-folder 19: 7)
  - 1080-1089, 1966 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - 1090-1099, 1966 (Box-folder 20: 2)
  - 1100-1109, 1966 (Box-folder 20: 3)
  - 1120-1129, 1966 (Box-folder 20: 4)
  - 1130-1139, 1966 (Box-folder 20: 5)
  - 1140-1149, 1966 (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - 1150-1159, 1966 (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - 1160, 1966 (Box-folder 21: 2)
- Edital de Matricula, 1966 (Box-folder 10: 4)
- Pesquisas em branco, circa 1966 (Box-folder 10: 5)
- Faculdades, 1966 (Box-folder 10: 6)
- Codigos, Universitários Nisseis, 1966 (Box-folder 10: 7)
- Relação de Alunos, 1966 (Box-folder 11: 5)
- Alunos Matriculados, 1966 (Box-folder 11: 6)
- The Japanese and Their Descendants in Brazil: An Annotated Bibliography, 1967 (Box-folder 18: 5)
- Sample #1 (Sao Paolo), circa 1966 (Box-folder 18: 6)
- Sample #2 (Lins), circa 1966 (Box-folder 18: 7)
- Nissei Universitarios interviews and field notes, circa 1966 (Box-folder 21: 3)
- Coopercotia Magazine, 1961-1967
  - 1961-1962 (Box-folder 23: 2)
  - 1963 (Box-folder 23: 3)
  - 1964 (Box-folder 23: 4)
  - 1965 (Box-folder 23: 5)
  - 1966 (Box-folder 23: 6)
  - 1967 (Box-folder 23: 7)
- Pamphlets for Cooperativo Agricola de Cotia, 1955-1967
  - undated (Box-folder 21: 4)
  - 1955 (Box-folder 21: 5)
  - 1956 (Box-folder 21: 6)
  - 1958 (Box-folder 21: 7)
  - 1959 (Box-folder 21: 8)
  - 1960 (Box-folder 21: 9)
  - 1961 (Box-folder 21: 10)
  - 1962 (Box-folder 22: 1)
  - 1963 (Box-folder 22: 2)
  - 1964 (Box-folder 22: 3)
  - 1965 (Box-folder 22: 4)
  - 1966 (Box-folder 22: 5)
  - 1967 (Box-folder 23: 1)
- Ethnic, Class, and Family Relations in Japanese Colonies in the Noroeste and Alta Paulista Frontier, Brazil (Box-folder 23: 8)
- Nissei Studies papers by John B. Cornell (Box-folder 23: 9)
- Card files, circa 1966-1967
  - Biographical and interpretive data cards by location, 1966-1967 (Box 24)
    Scope and Contents note
    Box 24 Contains data cards for the following locations and subjects (in order):
    São Paolo (reviewed) São Paolo (duplicates) Lins (Nisei) Lins (Japanese) São Paolo (Japanese-Brazilian Associations) Junqueirópolis Mirandópolis (Japanese-Brazilians)
  - Data cards on personal views and information, circa 1966 (Box 25)
    Contains cards for the following subjects and locations (under these labels):
    (500) Marriage and Family Duplicates for JBC Getulina: Potuguese Field Notes
  - Information cards and duplicates in Japanese by location, circa 1966 (Box 26)
    Locations for cards and duplicates
    In order:
    Mato Grosso Suzano, Seicho-no-le, Mirandópolis, Guatapará, Juquiá, Getulina, Santo Antonia da Platina
    Seicho-no-le is not a place, but a religion. Still, it was included as a subject amongst the others.
  - Information cards in Japanese by location, circa 1966 (Box 27)
    Locations
    Santo Antonio da Platina, City Getulina, City Getulina, Aliança Juquiá Matto Grosso Suzano, City
  - Duplicate information cards in Japanese by location, circa 1966 (Box 28)
    Junqueirópolis (Japanese) Junqueirópolis (Portuguese) Getulina (Portuguese) Guatapará (Portuguese) Suzano-Tijuco Preto Suzano (Japanese) Juquiá (Portuguese)
  - Information cards in Japanese by location, circa 1966 (Box 29)
    Locations and subjects
    Junqueirópolis, Yamato Junqueirópolis, City Junqueirópolis, Boa Vista Guatapará Mirandópolis, Aliança 1 Mirandópolis, Aliança 3 Mirandópolis, copy Juquiá (duplicates) Nisei Associations (São Paolo)
  - Numbered information cards, circa 1966 (Box 30)
    Numbering
    The cards numbered 0-499 and those numbered 600 and on are in this box. The 500 series is in Box 25 of the collection.
  - Information cards in Japanese, circa 1966 (Box 31)